Jun Xing (邢骏)

Senior Research Scientist, miHoYo (米哈游)

http://junxnui.github.io/

junxnui@gmail.com

RESEARCH

My research combines modern concepts in computer graphics, computer vision, machine learning and human computer interaction, with broad applications in 2D/3D/VR/Animation contents authoring, analysis, and synthesis. I am interested in designing interactive/predictive systems and deep learning-based algorithms to free the artists from the tedious works so they can focus on creation.

EDUCATION

University of Hong Kong 2012.09—2016.12

PhD in computer science, advised by Dr. Li-Yi Wei

University of Science and Technology of China (USTC) 2008.09—2012.06

Bachelor in Electronic Engineering and Information

WORK EXPERIENCE

miHoYo (米哈游) 2019.01—ongoing

Senior research scientist, Shanghai

USC Institute for Creative Technologies 2017.05 – 2019.01

Postdoctoral researcher, supervised by Hao Li, Vision and Graphics Lab, Los Angeles

Adobe Research 2016.07—2016.09

Graphics research intern, Procedural Imaging Group, San Jose

Autodesk Research 2016.01—2016.04

HCI Graphics research intern, UI Graphics Group, Toronto

Microsoft Research Asia 2014.12-2015.04

Graphics research intern, Visual Computing Group, Beijing

PUBLICATIONS

[13] HairBrush for Immersive Data-Driven Hair Modeling

Jun Xing, Koki Nagano, Weikai Chen, Haotian Xu, Li-Yi Wei, Jingwan Lu, Byungmoon Kim, Yajie Zhao, Hao Li UIST 2019

[12] Quantization Network

Jiwei Yang, Xu Shen, *Jun Xing*, Xinmei Tian, Houqiang Li, Bing Deng, Jianqiang Huang, Xiansheng Hua *CVPR 2019*

[11] Mask-off: Synthesizing Face Images in the Presence of Head-mounted Displays

Yajie Zhao, Qingguo Xu, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Chao Du, Xinyu Huang, Ruigang Yang *IEEE VR 2019*

[10] paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Lingyu Wei, Zimo Li, Shunsuke Saito, Aviral Agarwal, Jens Fursund, Hao Li *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018*

[9] HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Yi Zhou, Liwen Hu, *Jun Xing*, Weikai Chen, Han-Wei Kung, Xin Tong, Hao Li *ECCV 2018*

[8] Deep Volumetric Video from Very Sparse Multi-View Performance Capture

Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Yajie Zhao, *Jun Xing*, Chloe LeGendre, Linjie Luo, Chongyang Ma, Hao Li *ECCV 2018*

[7] Identity Preserving Face Completion for Large Ocular Region Occlusion

Yajie Zhao, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Xiaoming Li, Zach Bessinger, Fuchang Liu, Wangmeng Zuo, Ruigang Yang *BMVC 2018*

[6] Autocomplete 3D Sculpting

Mengqi Peng, *Jun Xing*, Li-Yi Wei *SIGGRAPH 2018*

[5] Mesoscopic Facial Geometry Inference using Deep Neural Networks

Loc Huynh, Weikai Chen, Shunsuke Saito, *Jun Xing*, Koki Nagano, Andrew Jones, Hao Li, Paul Debevec *CVPR 2018 (Spotlight)*

[4] Sequence-to-Sequence Learning via Shared Latent Representation

Xu Shen, Xinmei Tian, *Jun Xing*, Yong Rui, Dacheng Tao *AAAI 2018*

[3] Energy-Brushes: Interactive Tools for Illustrating Stylized Elemental Dynamics

Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice UIST 2016

[2] Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations

Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei, Takaaki Shiratori, and Koji Yatani SIGGRAPH Asia 2015

[1] Autocomplete Painting Repetitions

Jun Xing, Hsiang-Ting Chen and Li-Yi Wei SIGGRAPH Asia 2014

EXHIBITIONS

VR Hair Salon for Avatars

Jun Xing, Liwen Hu, Koki Nagano, Li-Yi Wei, Hao Li. SIGGRAPH 2019 Real-time Live!

Pinscreen Avatars in your Pocket: Mobile paGAN engine and Personalized Gaming

Koki Nagano, Shunsuke Saito, Mclean Goldwhite, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Liwen Hu, Lingyu Wei, *Jun Xing*, Qingguo Xu, Hanwei Kung, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Erik Castellanos, Jaewoo Seo, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018 Real-time Live!*

Deep Learning-Based Photoreal Avatars for Online Virtual Worlds in iOS

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Mclean Goldwhite, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Caleb Arthur, Hanwei Kung, Stuti Rastogi, Carrie Sun, Stephen Chen, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. SIGGRAPH 2018 Real-time Live!

MEDIA & PRESS

paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures

SIGGRAPH Asia 2018 Technica Papers Trailer; fxGuide; LA Times; CBS News; CBC News; Netflix Original and Buzzfeed; Channel One News; Cartoon Brew; NTV (Nippon TV) News;

HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Nvidia News; MIT Tech Review;

Autocomplete 3D Sculpting

3Dnchu; MIT Tech Review;

Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations

WIRED; FastCompany; The Next Web; AnimationWeek; MentalFloss; CoolThings; TechTimes; 3Dnchu; CGPress;

TECHNICAL REPORTS & PATENTS

Learning Perspective Undistortion of Portraits

Yajie Zhao, Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Chloe LeGendre, Xinglei Ren, *Jun Xing*, Ari Shapiro, Hao Li arXiv:1905.07515

Deep RBFNet: Point Cloud Feature Learning using Radial Basis Functions

Weikai Chen, Xiaoguang Han, Guanbin Li, Chao Chen, *Jun Xing*, Yajie Zhao, Hao Li arXiv:1812.04302.

Techniques for Generating Dynamic Effects Animations

Pending, US filed by Autodesk (2016), https://patents.justia.com/patent/20180082460

Stroke Operation Prediction for Three-Dimensional Digital Content

Pending, US filed by Adobe (2017), https://patents.justia.com/patent/20180239434

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Committee Member:

AAAI 2019

International Conference on Computational Visual Media (CVM) 2019

Pacific Graphics 2018

SIGGRAPH Emerging Technology 2017

Reviewer:

Computer Vision: ICCV 2019; CVPR 2019; ACCV 2018; IEEE Transactions on Image Processing;

Computer Graphics: SIGGRAPH Asia 2017; PG 2018, 2016, 2015; VRST 2018;

Human Computer Interaction: CHI 2017;

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Designer:

algorithm, system, UI/UX

Programmer:

C/C++, Qt, Python, Java, OpenGL/CV/VR, Unity

AWARDS

Adobe Research Fellowship Finalist	2016	
Excellent intern of Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program, Microsoft Research Asia	2015	
HKU University Postgraduate Fellowships, HKU	2012-2015	
Outstanding undergraduate, USTC	2012	
Outstanding undergraduate research project, USTC	2011	
Second prize in Mathematical Contest in Modeling	2011	
National Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China	2011	
National Inspirational Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China	2009, 2010	
Outstanding Students Scholarship, USTC	2008, 2009	

REFERENCES

Dr. Li-Yi Wei	Adobe Research, lwei@adobe.com
Prof. Hao Li	Pinscreen, USC, ICT, hao@hao-li.com
Dr. Rubaiat Habib Kazi	Adobe Research, rhabib@adobe.com
Prof Tovi Crossman	University of Toronto, tovi@dan toronto ed

Prof. Tovi Grossman University of Toronto, tovi@dgp.toronto.edu

Dr. Jos Stam Nvidia, stam.jos@gmail.com